■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
《反恐24小时》前情提要
Previously on 24
我们得牵制他并设法救出总统
We need to pick him off to try to save the president.
我跑到安全屋那儿
I'll make a run for the lockdown room.
那儿有5个装有甲烷的罐子
There are five canisters of ch-4.
只要一个流弹就够了
All we need is one stray bullet.
那等于自杀  杰克
A suicide play,jack.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
别动
Don't you move!
我们找到总统了
We have the president!
总统安全了
The president is secure!
我很遗憾  杰克
I'm so sorry,jack.
我知道他是你的好朋友
I know that he was your friend.
牺牲的本该是我
It was supposed to be me.
朱玛一伙还有同党
Juma and his men were not working alone.
现在唯一的线索就是莱恩·伯内特
And right now,the only lead we've got is ryan burnett.
他知道这次袭击的目标是白宫
He knew about the attack on the white house,
他很有可能知道  朱玛和谁通话
And chances are,he's gonna know who juma was talking to.
我正在考虑
I'm thinking about
让奥利维亚加入
Bringing olivia on  board
担任特别顾问
As a special advisor.
大选时她的所为大家都还历历在目
Nobody's forgotten what she did during the campaign.
她对媒体散布谣言
Leaking damaging personal information
诽谤您的竞选对手
About your opponent to the press.
她已痛改前非
She's changed.
我不计较过去
It's not the past that concerns me.
但如果我妈的政府里有个
Do you think any of this
称职的首席顾问  你觉得
Would've happened if my mother had a chief advisor
今天的一切还会发生吗
Who knew what the hell was going on in her administration?
我刚接到伊桑·卡宁的电话
I just got off the phone with ethan kanin.
他命令我让鲍尔去审问伯内特
He's ordering me to let bauer interrogate burnett.
听着  我不想背着你做事
Look,i didn't want to go behind your back,
但是你让我别无选择
But you didn't leave me any choice.
你给我回办公室收拾铺盖卷儿
I want you to clean out your office
并上交你的联邦探员徽章
And hand in your badge.
你被停职了
I'm suspending you.
杰克·鲍尔正在去肯尼迪纪念医院的路上
Jack bauer's on his way to kennedy memorial hospital.
伯内特一定会和盘托出
Burnett will tell him everything.
我已派人去医院
I have already sent somebody to the hospital
干掉伯内特
To deal with burnett.
他也会好好招呼鲍尔的
He can take care of bauer at the same time.
你动他一根汗毛  就别想再继续了
You lay one finger on him,it's over.
明白
Right.
朱玛已经玩完儿了
Juma's attack failed.
他跟他的同党都死翘翘了
He's dead,so are his men.
来人啊  救我
Somebody get me the hell out of here!
你哪也去不成了
You're not going anywhere.
怎么了
What happened?
出什么事了
What's going on?
该死  鲍尔  给我开门
Damn it,bauer,open the door!
优先发布捉拿杰克·鲍尔的全境缉捕通告
I want a high-priority APB issued for jack bauer.
拉里  我是杰克  听我说
Larry,it's jack. listen to me.
我是被陷害的
I'm being set up.
别让他们逍遥法外
Don't let them get away with this.
这次威胁还没有结束
This threat is not over.
以下事件发生于晚上9点到10点
The following takes place between 9 p.m. and 10 p.m.
5个小时前我开车送我妻子到这
I dropped my wife off here five hours ago,
现在却不知所踪
And now no one can tell me where she is.
奥布赖恩先生  白宫遭到了恐怖袭击
Mr. o'brian,the white house has been attacked.
我们正忙于处理紧急情况
We're in the midst of an urgent protocol.
是啊  所以我才要知道
Exactly. that's why i'd like to
我妻子是否安然无恙
know if my wife all right.
她很好  很安全
She is; she's fine.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
告诉我
Tell me.
她在三楼的关押室
She's in a holding room on the third floor.
-什么  -她被逮捕了
- What...? - she's been arrested.
太荒唐了
That's absurd.
凭什么抓她  我要见她
What's she charged with? i want to see her.
听着  你知道的已经够多了
Listen,i've already told you more than i should have.
等莫斯探员回来
When agent moss returns,he'll tell you
他会一五一十地告诉你
Everything you need to know.
现在  请你在会议室稍等一下  好吗
In the meanwhile,i'm gonna have to ask you to wait in the conference room,okay?
请吧  失陪了
Please. i'm sorry.
送他到会议室去
Please escort him to the conference room.
谢谢
Thank you.
詹尼斯  拉里打电话找你
Janis,larry's calling for you.
说是急事
He says it's urgent.
-几线  -3线
- What line? - three.
在这儿签字  证明你完全理解
Sign here,verifying you understand
关于你停职的各项条款
The terms of your suspension,
还有这里
And again here...
沃克探员
Agent walker?
继续  我听着呢
Go ahead, i'm listening.
拉里  我是詹尼斯
Larry,it's janis.
莱恩·伯内特死了
Ryan burnett is dead.
怎么会
How?
当时鲍尔正在审问他
Bauer was interrogating him when it happened,
我们得对这件事负责
And we're responsible.
你是说鲍尔杀了伯内特
You're saying that bauer killed burnett?
我不知道
I don't know.
我去抓他的时候他早跑了
He escaped before i could get to him.
他打来电话
He called me,said he was being
说自己是被陷害的  不愿认栽
set up and he wouldn't come in.
我找不到他  詹尼斯
I lost him,janis.
他跑了  我得把他找出来
I lost him,and it's on me to find him.
告诉我你需要什么
Just tell me what you need.
我已经向各部门优先发布了全境缉捕令
I already sent out a priority,all-agency APB.
你要继续追踪线索
I need you to follow up on that.
我现在就回办公室
I'm coming back to the office right now.
协调搜捕行动
I'll coordinate the search operation from there.
好的
Okay.
打开各部门公共频道
Open an all-agency channel
强调对杰克·鲍尔须展开迅速的追捕行动
With flags for immediate action on jack bauer.
我去通知地方警局也参与行动
I'll make sure the local police departments are linked in.
-我来处理  -谢谢
- On it. - thank you.
詹尼斯  拉里说什么了
Janis,what did larry say?
杰克从伯内特口中问出什么了吗
Jack get anything out of burnett?
你已经被停职了
You're suspended.
我不能跟你讨论这个
I cannot discuss this with you.
詹尼斯  这曾是我的案子
Janis,this was my case.
告诉我杰克到底问出了什么
Tell me if jack got anything out of burnett.
伯内特死了
Burnett is dead.
怎么回事
Well,tell me what happened.
鲍尔当时在场  现在他不知所踪了
Bauer was there,and now he's missing.
詹尼斯  频道都开了
Janis,the channel's open.
谢谢
Thank you.
我只知道这些  真的
That's all i know,honestly.
拜托  让我回去干活吧  行吗
So,please,let me get back to work,okay?
把杰克·鲍尔的资料附到通缉令上
Please attach jack bauer's profile to the apb.
找着你了
Got you.
沃克
Walker.
蕾妮  我是杰克
Renee,it's jack.
请别挂电话
Don't hang up the phone,please.
无论他们怎么说  我都没有杀伯内特
Whatever they told you,i did not kill burnett.
蕾妮
Renee?
我在
Yeah.
比尔说的没错
Bill was right.
在杜巴库的磁盘中
There are still very powerful people
还有不为人知的权势显赫的人物
Involved in this conspiracy that were not named
参与到这场阴谋当中
In dubaku's drive.
为了掩盖罪行
They're trying to cover their tracks.
他们杀了伯内特  让我背黑锅
They killed burnett,and they're framing me for it.
杰克  不是我不想帮你
Even if i wanted to help you,jack,
拉里在方圆100英里内动用全部警力
Larry has every law enforcement agency within 100 miles
抓捕你  而且我已经被停职了
Looking for you,and i have been suspended.
我只要你帮我查一个人
All i want you to do is make an i.d.
我从医院的监控录像上截取了一张图像
I got a frame grab from the hospital's surveillance.
我把杀害伯内特的凶手照片发给你
I sent you a photo of the man who did kill burnett.
在你的收件箱里
It's in your inbox.
蕾妮  此人是能帮我们找出这次事件
Renee,this man is the only connection i have to whoever else
幕后指使的唯一线索
Is involved in this thing.
求你了  我需要你的帮助
Please,i need your help.
我知道你对我今天的行事方式有意见
Look, i know you don't agree with some of thing i did today.
但是我跟你说的是事实
But... i'm telling you the truth.
蕾妮
Renee?
你知道吗
You know what?
算了  抱歉
Forget it. i'm-i'm sorry.
我找错人了
I made a mistake.
我一会打给你
I'll call you back at this number.
首府警察
Metro police,
这里是联邦调查局的通告
This is the fbi reporting.
嫌犯杰克·鲍尔已从拘押中逃脱
We have a suspect,jack bauer,that's escaped custody.
所有小队  收到请回答
All available units,please respond.
奎恩  请讲
Yes,quinn.
鲍尔从联邦调查局跑了
Bauer got away from the fbi.
怎么回事
How?
鲍尔是名身手不凡的探员
Well,bauer is an extremely impressive operative.
这点不用你来提醒我
You don't have to tell me that.
联邦调查局正在全力抓捕他
But the fbi has launched a major effort to apprehend him.
他撑不了多久的
He won't be able to avoid them for long.
静观其变吧
Well,we'll see,won't we?
继续追踪情况  及时反馈
Monitor the situation,keep me apprised.
是的  先生
Yes,sir.
如果鲍尔把我们和朱玛联系上
If bauer connects us to juma,
会严重阻碍这次行动
It could seriously impede this operation.
没错
Yes,it could.
货能准时送到吗
Is the shipment on time?
是的  一个小时后到港
Yes. due into port in the next hour.
那就没问题了
Then I don't foresee a problem.
一旦武器部署到位
Once the weapons are deployed,
鲍尔和其他人知道与否就无关紧要了
Then it doesn't matter what mr. bauer or anyone else knows.
还有问题吗
Something wrong?
没有了  先生
No,sir.
西顿先生  想到这么多人会命丧我手
Mr. seaton,I get no pleasure
我也深感内疚和痛苦
From the knowledge that people will die at our hands.
死去的每一个人  对我来说都是一场悲剧
One single soul,the loss of one soul is tragic to me,
更别说是这么大的一个伤亡数字
Let alone the numbers we're talking about!
但你不要忘了
But do not forget that every war
任何战争都会有附带伤亡的
Worth fighting involves collateral damage.
而且我们现在做的事
And what we're doing
从根本意义上来说是绝对必要的
Is fundamentally and absolutely necessary!
我希望你清楚这点
And I know you understand that!
当然
Of course.
叫醒同事们
Wake up our colleagues
让他们在一小时之内集合
And have them assembled in one hour.
告诉他们带上睡衣和牙刷
And tell them to pack their pajamas and their toothbrushes.
今夜会很漫长
It's gonna be a long night.
请讲
Yeah?
-查到了  -是谁
- I have an I.D. - Who is it?
约翰·奎恩
John quinn.
参与秘密行动的退伍老兵
Black ops combat vet.
在世界各地都执行过任务
Served tours all over the world.
现在他在斯塔克伍德公司供职
Now he works for starkwood.
国防部的顾问公司吗
The defense consultant?
是的  他们开始只是搞咨询服务
Uh,yeah,they started out as consultants,
但在过去你身处异国他乡的几年里
But over the past few years,while you were
五角大楼外包了许多
Out of the country,the pentagon outsourced
亿万美元的合同给他们
Billions of dollars in contracts to them.
什么样的合同
What kind of contracts?
人力资源输出
Manpower.
斯塔克伍德公司本质上就是一支私人军队
Starkwood's basically a private army.
他们从世界各地
They recruit ex-soldiers and swat team members
招募了许多退役士兵和反恐特警
From around the world,
雇佣他们组成军事安保小组
Then they hire them back to the military security teams.
成千上万的特警驻扎在国内外
We're talking thousands of men deployed here and abroad.
斯塔克伍德和朱玛是一伙的吗
Starkwood work with juma?
即使是  也根本无案可查
Well,if they did,it wasn't on the books.
但若有人知情  就一定是迈尔参议员
But,you know,if anyone knows,it's senator mayer.
为什么是他
Why mayer?
解散了反恐小组之后
After he dismantled ctu,
他又开始了一系列的调查
He launched several other investigations.
斯塔克伍德公司也在其中
One of them has been looking at starkwood.
指控的罪名是什么
What were they accused of?
听证会是保密的
The hearings are classified,but
但想必迈尔该有足够的证据搞垮他们
Supposedly,mayer has enough to put them out of business.
好的  我现在就去找他谈
Okay,i'm gonna need to talk to him.
能否查下紧急事件反应小组的记录
See if you can access the CIRG logs.
应该可以找到他的位置
They should have a location on him.
好的  我找到之后马上发给你
Okay. i'll send you mayer's location as soon as i have it.
谢谢
Thanks.
沃克探员还在这吗
Agent walker still here?
她在她的办公室
She was just in her office.
但有个人在会议室
But there's somebody waiting to see you
等着见你  他们要...
In the conference room. they need to...
[紧急事件反应小组  白宫访客明细]
Critical Incident Response Group-White House Guest Status.
[参议员布莱恩·迈尔  转移到私人宅邸]
Senator Blaine Mayer. In transit to private residence.
[任务加密并发送]
Encrypt and send operation.
我还有几个表格要填
Just have a few more forms to fill out,
填好我就走
Then I'm taking off.
你知道发生在医院的事了吗
You hear what happened at the hospital?
杰克今天为我们做了这么多
After everything that jack's done today,
你真的相信他杀了伯内特吗
Do you really believe that he murdered Burnett?
我不知道
I don't know.
我  我不在乎
I... I don't care.
他是联邦政府逃犯  必须抓他归案
He's a federal fugitive and needs to be found.
但你觉得有可能是他杀的吗
But you think it's possible that he did this?
因为我不太能相信这点
'Cause I'm not sure I do.
真是漫长的一天
It's been a long day.
回家睡觉去吧
Go home,get some sleep.
-明早我会打电话给你  -好的
- I'll call you in the morning. - Okay.
打扰一下  拉里
Excuse me,Larry.
莫里斯·奥布赖恩正在会议室等你
Morris o'brian is waiting in the conference room.
他想知道我们为什么关押克洛伊
He wants to know why his wife is in holding.
蕾妮和鲍尔通过话了
Renee talked to bauer.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
检查她最近15分钟的电话记录
Access her phone log for the last 15 minutes
进入她的工作站  看看她到底在干什么
And get into her workstation, find out what she's been doing
好的
All right.
要抓住鲍尔  她是我们的最佳途径
If we want to catch bauer,she's our best shot.
知道了
Okay.
有消息确认泰勒总统
We've received confirmation that president taylor
稍后会发表全国演说
will be making a statement to the country shortly.
她将陈述1小时前刚从一场惊心动魄的救援中
She is expected to address the attack on the white house
结束的针对白宫的袭击事件
that ended an hour ago in a startling rescue.
目前  据我们现有的少量情报来看
Now,based on the few details we have,
我们已确认  朱玛和他的部队
We do know the rescue resulted in the death
在这次救援行动中已被尽数歼灭
Of general juma and all of his forces.
安吉拉  我写完修正稿后
Angela,how much lead time does the media need,
媒体还要多久准备好
Once I'm finished with my revisions?
主流媒体会即刻播出我们的演讲
The major outlets will put us on immediately.
我马上就好了
I'll be done shortly.
安吉拉  谢谢
Thank you,angela.
您要不要听一下
I have a thought
我对这次演说的建议
About the speech,if you'd like to hear it.
当然了
Of course.
现在您演说的首要目的就是要安抚民众
Right now your main thrust is reassurance.
危机已经过去
The attacks are behind us,
一切将恢复正常
Everything's going to be back to normal.
但我认为您错失了一个良机
But I think you're missing an opportunity here.
是做什么的良机呢
To do what?
宣布胜利
Claim victory.
声明朱玛的死意味着  勇敢地起来
To say that juma's death means standing up
抵抗暴政的行为立竿见影了
To tyranny works,
而您出兵桑加拉的决定是正确的
and that your decision to send troops into sangala was the right one.
我认为现在并不是
I'm not sure that this is
欢呼雀跃的恰当时机  利维
The appropriate time to sound triumphant,livy.
今天很多人失去了生命
A lot of lives were lost today.
您对亡灵的追悼  将令他们死得其所
And by addressing those deaths,you give them meaning.
那些人是英雄豪杰
Those people are heroes
他们为正义的战争而牺牲
Who died in a war that was worth fighting.
好吧  我会加上去的
Let's work it in.
请进
Come in.
总统阁下  我有个坏消息
Madam president,i have some troubling news.
可以和您单独谈谈吗
May i speak with you alone?
你可以在奥利维亚面前直说
You my speak freely in front of olivia.
在白宫遇袭之后
Just after the attack on the white house,
杰克·鲍尔提供了
Jack bauer came forward
一个令人堪忧的情报
With a disturbing claim.
他说还有一些涉案人员
He said there were people
仍然逍遥法外
Still at large who were involved in the conspiracy--
正是这些不知名的家伙帮助朱玛
Persons unknown who had helped juma
策划并实施了这次袭击
Plan and execute the attacks.
鲍尔有证据吗
Did bauer have any evidence of this?
没有确凿的证据
Nothing concrete.
但他认为莱恩·伯内特
But he promoted the notion that ryan burnett
是我们找出这些人的最佳机会
Was our best chance of identifying these people,
鲍尔要求我授权去审讯他
And bauer asked to be allowed to question him.
情况本该在掌控之中
This was supposed to be a controlled situation.
本打算设计让他威胁伯内特如实招供
A ploy to intimidate burnett into giving up intel.
所以我同意了鲍尔的请求
So,I granted bauer's request.
但我铸成了大错
It was a terrible mistake.
伊桑  发生什么事了
What happened,ethan?
伯内特死了
Burnett is dead.
天哪
My god...
证据表明  他是被鲍尔所杀
The evidence suggests that he was killed by bauer.
我不相信
I don't believe it!
他声称参与这次阴谋的另有其人
His claim of another party being involved in the attacks
这话看起来是一个谎言
Appear to have been a fabrication.
谎言
A fabrication.
这可能与比尔·布坎南的死有关
It may have something to do with bill buchanan's death;
没人知道
No one knows.
但是总统阁下
But madam president,
我将对我的行为承担全部责任
I take full responsibility.
我试图不告诉您是因为
I was trying to insulate you.
万一出了岔子  您可以推诿说不知情
To provide you with deniability in case anything went wrong.
或是因为你认为总统会反对你的做法吧
Or was it because you thought the president would say no?
奥利维亚
Olivia.
鲍尔现在在哪里
Where is bauer now?
依旧在逃
At large.
调查局正全力追捕他
The fbi is devoting its full resources to the manhunt.
一旦找到他  马上向我汇报
Let me know the minute they find him.
好的  阁下
Yes,ma'am.
总统阁下
Madam president...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
看起来东西都齐了
Looks like everything.
她要走了
She's on the move.
鲍尔在哪里
Where's bauer?
我不知道
I don't know.
不要对我撒谎
Don't you lie to me.
我们追踪到你给一个
We traced two calls from your cell
挂失的手机打了两通电话
To a phone that was reported stolen.
我们也查出你进入了政府机密数据库
And we know you accessed a classified government database
还把某人的姓名和地址发给鲍尔
And sent someone's name and address to bauer.
蕾妮  这样一来你成了事后从犯了
Renee,that makes you an accessory after the fact.
告诉我他在哪
Now tell me where he is.
我做不到
I can't.
-该死  -我还是不信是他干的
- Damn it! - I still don't believe that he did this.
那解释下他为什么不自首
Then explain to me why he's not turning himself in,
让我们帮他找到那莫须有的第三方
And letting us help him find this mysterious third party.
因为他被陷害而且他不相信
Because he was framed and he doesn't trust
我们能为他洗脱罪名
Our ability to work through it.
在我们对他那般地不公后
And,you know,after what we've put him through,
我们怎能再责备他呢
How can you blame him?
你真愿为保全他而牺牲一切吗
You're actually willing to sacrifice everything to protect him.
杰克找到证据后  他会给我们打电话的
Once jack finds the evidence,he will call us.
詹尼斯在破译你发出的信息
You know,janis is decrpyting what you sent.
用不了多久
It's not going to take her a long time.
我们就会找到他的
We are going to find him.
蕾妮  告诉我你发的是谁的资料
Renee,tell me whose information you sent.
我会告诉司法部长  你很合作
I'll let the A.G. know that you're cooperating.
抱歉  拉里
I'm sorry,larry.
把她关起来
Put her in holding.
告知她所享有的合法权利
Mirandize her.
晚安  先生
Good night,sir.
明早见
See you in the morning.
有人吗
Hello?
把你的手放在我看得到的地方   参议员
Keep your hands where i can see them,senator.
鲍尔
Bauer.
坐下
Take a seat.
我知道你对莱恩·伯内特都做了什么
I know what you did to ryan burnett.
我不会让你那样杀了我的
I'm not going to let you butcher me like you did him.
你想我死的话  鲍尔
You want me dead,bauer,
那你就在这动手吧
You'll have to kill me where i stand.
参议员  如果我想杀你 你早就死了
If i wanted to kill you,senator, You'd be dead already.
给我坐下
Now take a seat!
你真让人费解  鲍尔
You're a real enigma,bauer.
在你把总统从恐怖分子魔掌中救出的1小时后
An hour after you save the president from terrorists,
你却残忍地杀害了一名联邦证人
You murder a federal witness in cold blood.
我没杀伯内特
I didn't kill burnett.
是他干的
This man did.
你知道他是谁吗
Do you know who he is?
不知道
No.
他叫约翰·奎恩
His name is john quinn.
他为斯塔克伍德公司卖命
He works for starkwood.
这和斯塔克伍德公司有什么联系
What in the world does starkwood have to do with this?
我还不清楚
I don't know yet.
但我知道他们派人杀了伯内特
But i do know they sent someone to kill burnett
并陷害我来掩盖他们
And frame me to cover up their involvement
今天所策划的一切阴谋诡计
In everything that's happened today,
包括这次对白宫的袭击
Including the attack on the white house.
鲍尔  这简直是天方夜谭
That's a hell of a theory,bauer.
但如果你妄想以此洗脱罪名的话
But you'll have to spin a better story than that
那你还得给我编个更好的故事吧
If you expect it to get you off the hook.
参议员  我不是来为自己证明清白的
Senator,i did not come here to clear my name.
我只想搞清楚
I'm trying to understand
朱玛和斯塔克伍德之间的联系
The connection between juma and starkwood.
没有任何联系
There isn't one.
我花了6个月的时间来调查斯塔克伍德
I've spent the better part of six months investigating starkwood.
如果和朱玛或桑加拉有关的话
If there was a connection to juma or sangala,
我早就知道了
I would know it.
我想看下你们所有相关的调查文件
I want to see every file you have concerning that investigation.
听着
Look...
斯塔克伍德公司纵容其安保队
Starkwood has let their security teams run amok
在全世界胡作非为  却坐视不管
All over the world,with no oversight.
他们试图以贿赂取得大项目的订单
They've bribed their way into large contracts,
他们试图干涉外交政策来为己所用
They've tried to influence foreign policy to their own benefit--
这就是为什么这个国家不该把军事行动
all good reasons Why this country should not be outsourcing
外包给私人企业的原因
Its military operations to private corporations.
我会让他们关门大吉的
And i am going to shut them down.
但没有任何证据表明
But there is nothing to remotely suggest
他们和本次针对祖国的恐怖袭击有牵连
They'd be involved in terrorist attacks on their own country
他们绝不会为钱出卖国家
For any amount of money.
他们帮助朱玛可能另有所图
Maybe they have different reasons for helping juma.
图什么
Like what?
我不知道
I don't know.
先生  我相信这个国家还会受到攻击
Sir,i believe this country is still under attack,
而这一切一定有一个合理的解释
And there has to be a reason.
难道我该相信一个绑架我的人的鬼话吗
And i'm supposed to believe this, coming from a man who's holding me hostage?
我要查看那些文件
I need access to those files.
如果朱玛和斯塔克伍德之间没有牵连
And if the connection Between juma and starkwood isn't there,
你愿意自首吗
Will you turn yourself in,then?
打开文件  先生
Just open the files,sir.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
总统今晚会发表一个简短的讲话
The president will be making a brief statement tonight.
祝你好运  妈
Good luck,mom.
我相信你们会理解  基于今天发生的事件
I'm sure you'll understand, based on the events of today,
讲话后没有提问的环节
There will be no opportunity for follow-up questions.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
总统阁下驾到
The president of the united states.
谢谢你们
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Thank you.
亲爱的美国同胞们  约翰·亚当斯
My fellow americans,john adams,
第一位在白宫居住的总统
The first president to take up residence in the white house,
曾向上苍祈福
Once prayed for heaven to bestow
祈祷白宫永享太平
Its blessings on this place.
今晚  上天保佑  让我们从
Tonight,those blessings have seen us through
一群玩命之徒的袭击中化险为夷
A brutal attack by a desperate tyrant.
我们失去了朋友和所爱的人
We have lost friends and loved ones here,
但我们胜利了
But we have prevailed.
我已经命令执法机构
I have commanded law enforcement agencies,
突发事件处理部门及其反应小组
Emergency services and first responders
时刻准备着
To keep their deployment level...
卡宁先生  我是肯·德奥  CNB的记者
Mr. kanin,ken dellao,cnb.
你能否确认下我刚收到的一条消息
I'm wondering if you can confirm some information I received a short time ago?
肯  现在真不是时候
Ken,this is clearly not the time...
我想在今晚的报道中播出
Yeah,i'm,i'm going to be reporting in this evening's broadcast
一名叫杰克·鲍尔的前联邦探员
That a rogue ex-federal agent named jack bauer
涉嫌谋杀了莱恩·伯内特
Is the prime suspect in the murder of ryan burnett.
...无法忘记今天的事件
...cannot forget today's events.
那些牺牲的生命...
The lives we lost...
你从哪听到的
Where did you get this?
这么说是真的了
So,it's true,then?
我没这么说
I'm not confirming anything.
我还会报道  是您授权释放了鲍尔
I'll also be reporting that you authorized bauer's release from custody
并安排他接近受害者
And arranged for his access to the victim.
儿女们  兄弟姐妹们
...daughters and sons,brothers and sisters,
但他们夺不走我们的灵魂
But they have not taken our spirit.
没错  今天的袭击
Make no mistake,today's attacks
本来是企图摧毁我们的决心
Were intended to crush our resolve.
卡宁先生
Mr. kanin.
我说过  无可奉告
I said no comment.
但美国绝不会那么轻易屈服
But america is not so easily broken.
我们在桑加拉的军事行动已大获全胜
Our military action in sangala has been a success.
此时此刻  我们的部队
At this hour,our forces
已经控制了桑加拉
have taken control of sangala city.
我们赢了
We have won.
看来你又在耍老把戏了
I see you're back to your old tactics.
你把伯内特的死
You leaked the story of burnett's murder
还有我的介入都透露给了媒体
And my involvement to the press.
伊桑  我不知道你在说什么
Ethan,i don't know what you're talking about.
奥利维亚  别想抵赖了
Olivia,don't bother denying it.
知道我授权释放鲍尔的人屈指可数
I can count on one hand the number of people who knew i'd authorized bauer's release.
那么你的又一次判断失误
So another one of your errors in judgment
让你搬起石头砸了自己的脚
bites you on the ass.
你还妄想把责任推到我身上
And you think you can lay the blame on me.
你知道这么做的后果吗
Do you realize what you've done?
为了伤害我
In trying to hurt me,
你会严重地伤害你母亲
You'll have caused tremendous damage to your mother.
总统一向是公开反对
The president has gone on record
任何情况下的刑讯逼供的
That torture is unacceptable under any circumstances.
这事一旦曝光  看上去鲍尔
When this gets out,it will look like bauer was sent
就是被派去折磨犯人的
Exactly for that.
这将成为一场政治浩劫
It'll be a political disaster.
你这次玩过头了
You've gone too far this time.
我受够你的唠叨了
I'm not listening to you anymore.
我不会让你轻易得逞的
I'm not going to let you get away with this.
把你的手放开
Get your hands off me.
作为美国人  我们应该同舟共济
As americans, We should stand together
为我们的成就感到自豪
proud of what we have achieved.
感谢那些今晚  在我们祖国大地上
Thanks to the efforts and the sacrifices
不屈不挠  抛头颅洒热血的
Of so many,this place,our national home,
仁人志士们
Stands tall tonight.
我们的人民可以安然入睡了
And all our citizens can sleep soundly with the knowledge
因为自由的荣光仍在闪耀
That the blessings of freedom continue to shine upon us all.
没有  东北区域不见鲍尔的踪影
No,there's been no sign of bauer in the northeast sector,
把警戒线范围扩展到25英里标记处
So expand your cordon to the 25-mile mark.
做好支援首府警局的准备
And be prepared to back up metro.
我正叫他们在全城随机抽查过往车辆
I'm directing them to begin random traffic stops,citywide.
谢谢
Thank you.
我把蕾妮传给鲍尔的数据分离出来了
I isolated the data renee uploaded to bauer,
但文件标题后的内容我就进不去了
But i can't get past the file header.
什么意思
What does that mean?
她把姓名地址都加密了
She encrypted the name and address she used,
我解不开
And i can't seem to crack it.
-解不开吗  -她用的是她的个人电脑
- You can't? - she used her personal computer.
这个加密非常复杂
This is very serious encryption.
-只有一些高手才能做到  -谁能
- I mean,there are some high-level people who can do it. - like who?
克罗伊·奥布赖恩  但你告诉我
Chloe o'brian-- but from what you've
她对鲍尔忠心不二
told me,she's too loyal to Bauer.
她丈夫还在这里吗
Is her husband still here?
是的  他正等着见你呢
Yeah. He's waiting to see you.
档案上显示他也是六级分析员
According to her file,he's a level-six analyst,too.
我不知道还要在这里待多久
I have no idea how much longer i'm going to be here.
帮我个忙好吗  在你把普雷斯科特
Just do me a favor and give prescott his babu
放上床睡觉前  把巴布熊给他
Before you put him down.
好的  我迟些打给你
Yeah,i'm going to have to call you back. yeah.
奥布赖恩先生  我是拉里·莫斯
Mr. o'brian,i'm larry moss.
我想要见我妻子
Yeah,i'd like to see my wife.
没问题
All right.
你们凭什么关她
What the bloody hell are you holding her for?
妨碍公务  篡改证据
Obstruction,evidence tampering.
我觉得你更应该考虑的是
I think you should be more concerned about
-怎么把她弄出来  -什么
- What you can do to get her out. - sorry?
帮我们找到杰克·鲍尔
Help us find jack bauer.
上次克洛伊提到他时
Last i heard from chloe,
杰克还在为局里工作
jack was working for the bureau.
如果我没弄错的话  他是为你办事
That's you,if i'm not mistaken.
以前是
He was.
直到他突然失控  杀了一个联邦证人
Until he snapped and murdered a federal witness.
真的吗
Really?
我很难相信
I find that hard to believe.
当前最重要的是
All that's relevant here is that your wife
你妻子会因跟鲍尔串谋而被起诉
Is going to be prosecuted for colluding with bauer,
除非你帮我们找到他
Unless you help us find him.
奥布赖恩先生
Mr. o'brian,
不久前
A short time ago,
我们的一个探员跟杰克·鲍尔联系过
One of our agents was in touch with jack bauer.
她发了一个地址和名字给他
She sent a name and address
我们判断杰克应该是去那了
That we assume is his next destination.
很不幸  这是用河豚148算法加密的
Unfortunately,it's encrypted with blowfish 148.
这里的人都不知道怎么破解
No one here knows how to crack that.
所以我们需要你的帮助
Therefore,we need your help.
请帮帮我们
Please.
你们得知道
You have to understand something.
杰克·鲍尔跟我太太的交情甚笃
Jack bauer and my wife have a very long history.
我也把他当做朋友
I consider him to be a friend.
他会有在法庭上申诉的机会的
And he'll have his day in court.
但你太太的这个案子是铁证如山
But the case against your wife is rock solid.
我办不到
I can't.
你太太面临的是至少15年的监禁
We're talking about her serving a minimum sentence of 15 years.
她出狱的时候你儿子都19岁了
Your son will be 19 by the time she gets out of prison.
我要份完全豁免权的担保书
I want guarantees of full immunity,
不用坐牢  撤销所有指控和案底
No jail time,expulsion of all charges from her record.
我答应你
You have my word.
-你是这份协议的见证人  -好的
- You are a witness to this agreement. - Yes.
给我看看文件
Show me the file.
原始信息是16位还是32位字长的
Original information-- 16- or 32-bit word length?
32位的
thirty-two.
是原始的还是修改的数据点
Native or modified data points?
原始的
Native.
这个算法的设计者
The designer of this algorithm
在他的代码里植入了后门程序
Built a backdoor into his code.
如果你知道超驰代码  解密就轻而易举
Decryption's a piece of cake if you know the override codes.
你知道
And you do?
当然
Yeah.
要很久吗
Will this take long?
当然不会
Course not.
奥布赖恩先生  你能确切告诉我们
Mr. o'brian,can you tell me specifically
什么时候这份文件能解密完
When you'll have the file decrypted?
好的
Yes.
解完了
Now.
你的探员让杰克去乔治敦
Your agent sent jack to
迪尔布鲁克大街951号
951 deerbrook avenue,georgetown,
参议员布莱恩·迈尔的住宅
Residence of senator blaine mayer.
召集外勤小组  告诉他们鲍尔的位置
Assemble the field teams. Tell them we have a probable location on bauer.
叫首府警局也开始行动
And get metro pd on the way.
迈尔的手机接不通
No luck reaching mayer on his cell
家里电话也一样
or at the house.
电话公司说  那边的线路短路了
The phone company said the line was shorted out on-site.
没错  准是鲍尔干的
Yeah,that's bauer.
他为什么这么做
Why is he doing this?
因为过去的6个月以来
Because mayer spent the last six months
迈尔一直想让鲍尔在狱中度过余生
Trying to send bauer to prison for the rest of his life.
好吧  首府警局正赶往迈尔的住宅
All right,metro pd is closing in on mayer's residence.
我已批准  一旦到齐就位  就冲进去
I've authorized them to move in as soon as they're in position and at strength.
我提醒过他们
I told them,
也提醒下你们  不要低估鲍尔
and i'm telling you,it is impossible to overestimate bauer.
他训练有素  经验老道
He has more training and more experience
比我们这里  包括我在内的任何人都要强
Than anybody in this room,and that includes myself.
好了  开始行动
Okay,let's move.
莫斯探员将会跟联邦探员一起
Agent moss will be running on-point tactical
在5号频道执行高级战术行动
with fbi teams on five.
所有小组都必须将通话频道与我连接
All units must register and log their com through me,
我会分发识别码和认证码
And i will distribute recognition codes and credentials.
-克罗伊  -简直无法相信
- Chloe... - i can't believe you.
你竟然帮他们抓杰克
You're helping them catch jack.
我都是为了你
I did it for you.
这是我最不想要你做的
This is the last thing i would have wanted.
-你怎么做得出来  -想想看  起先
- How could you do this?  - let's see,for a start,
我想  也许普雷斯科特就不必因为有个
I thought it might be nice to spare prescott
罪犯妈妈而给他带来诸多不便了
The inconvenience of having a convict for a mother.
-杰克救过你  -我并没有否认  我欠他的
- Jack saved your life. - i don't deny that i owe him.
但我的孩子跟婚姻是第一位的
But my child and my marriage comes first,
你也应该这么想
And it should for you,too.
克罗伊  你帮杰克够多了
Chloe,love,you've helped jack enough.
真的
You have.
你不能再自作主张牺牲自己了
And you can't go deciding to make this sacrifice on your own any more.
但他并没有干过他们说的那些事啊
But he didn't do what they're saying he did.
那么他被捕后可以再证明自己清白
Then he can prove that when they take him into custody.
那也要他们给他机会才行
If they give him the chance.
今早的听证会上
At the hearing this morning,
你说你对自己的所作所为无怨无悔
you said you had no regrets about what you've done.
但我看到的是一个极度悔恨的人
But what i saw was a man full of regret.
参议员  我当然有悔恨的事
Of course i have regrets,senator.
我悔恨失去了家庭
I regret losing my family.
我妻子被杀是因为我负责保护
My wife was murdered because i was responsible
戴维·帕默尔免遭刺杀
For protecting david palmer during an assassination attempt.
我的女儿现在甚至都不能看我一眼
My daughter can't even look at me.
每天  我都后悔瞥见的那一双双世人的眼睛
Every day,i regret looking into the eyes of men,women and children,
我深知  或许就在下一刻
Knowing that,any moment,
他们就会被当做牺牲品
Their lives might be deemed expendable
只为维护那更高的利益
In an effort to protect the greater good.
我后悔每一个造成
I regret every decision or mistake i might have made
无辜生命死亡的决定或错误
That resulted in the loss of a single innocent life.
但你知道我最后悔的是什么吗
But you know what i regret the most?
是这个世界还需要像我这样的人
Is that this world even needs people like me.
所以你觉得我会天真到去相信
So you think i'm naive to believe
我们要为一个更高的标准而战斗吗
We need to hold ourselves to a higher standard of combat?
我怎么想不重要  参议员
Doesn't even matter what i think,senator.
你只需要理解我工作的地方
You just need to understand where i work,
比你的国会要肮脏得多
Things get a lot messier than where you work on the hill.
鲍尔  你遭受的那些是个悲剧
What you've lost,mr. bauer,is tragic.
以拯救无辜生命之名
What you've been compelled to do
你被迫所做的一切都是悲剧
In the name of saving innocent life is tragic.
有时候我们需要经受最可怕的炼狱
Sometimes we need to incur the most horrible losses
就为了坚持理想
In order to uphold the ideals
这些理想是我们国家的基石
That this country was founded on.
要是我们不以身作则
How can we presume to lead the world
怎么还有脸引领世界
Unless we set an example?
你说得轻巧
You make it sound so simple.
也许就是比你想的简单
Well,maybe it's simpler than you think.
也许你所看到的和你所做的一切
Maybe all the things that you've seen and all the things that you've done
已经蒙蔽了你的双眼
have clouded your vision.
看这个
Look at this.
给我说说这起车祸
Tell me about this car accident.
这跟朱玛没关系
That has nothing to do with juma.
受害者是谁
Who was the victim?
一个安插在斯塔克伍德里的线人
A source inside of starkwood. A whistle-blower.
不幸的是  他还是个酒鬼
Unfortunately,he was also a drunk.
在他从大西洋城回家的路上
He was killed when he wrecked his car
出车祸死了
On the way home from atlantic city.
血液酒精含量超标
Blood alcohol off the charts.
参议员  这绝对不是事故
Senator,this was no accident.
杀你线人的跟今晚
Your informant was murdered by the same man
杀伯内特的是同一个人
Who took ryan burnett out this evening.
这意味着什么呢  鲍尔
What does this mean,bauer?
他们怕他泄密
They were scared of what he had to say.
你的线人到底知道斯塔克伍德什么秘密
What does your informant have on starkwood?
他提出过很多轻率的指控
He made a lot of wild accusations,
但是没一次是可以告倒他们的
But not a single one of them panned out.
或许是因为你查得不够深
Maybe you didn't dig deep enough.
参议员  我要知道他究竟告诉你什么了
Senator,i need to know exactly what he told you.
他声称斯塔克伍德
He alleged that starkwood
在勒索五角大楼的官员
Was blackmailing pentagon officials.
说他们涉嫌暗杀
That they were involved in assassination plots.
甚至说他们企图得到大规模杀伤性武器
Even that they were seeking to acquire their own wmds.
具体的是什么
Specifically what?
我记不清了  但我确信
Well,i don't remember,but i'm sure
电脑里应该有和他接头时的记录
That his interview transcript should be there.
好的  我找到了
Okay,i got it.
天哪
Oh,my god.
这就是了
That's it.
什么
What?
你的线人声称斯塔克伍德公司
Your informant claims that starkwood
企图获得生化武器
Was trying to acquire a bioweapon.
这就能联系上朱玛了
That's your connection to juma.
我不明白
I don't understand.
朱玛掌权的时候  传闻他在
When juma was in power,it was rumored
实施一项研制非法武器的计划
That he was running an illegal weapons program.
他在研发一种生化武器
He was developing a bioweapon,
但没有人能证明
But nobody could prove it.
但是我在桑加拉时认识的人
But the people that i knew in sangala
坚信朱玛在拿自己的国民做实验
Believed he was testing these weapons on his own population.
他在一个偏僻的山村里释放了一种病菌
He used a remote village, Released some kind of pathogen.
那里所有的人变得痴呆
Everyone there was struck with dementia,
然后瘫痪  直至死亡
Paralysis and eventually died.
为什么没人追究
Why wasn't this pursued?
因为朱玛毁灭了所有的证据
'cause juma destroyed all the evidence.
他抢先一步  用燃烧弹把那里夷为了平地
He firebombed the village  before anyone could get there,
联合国的官员也总是很难相信
and UN officials had a hard time believing that juma had the technology
朱玛有技术和专长造出这样的武器
Or expertise to develop such a weapon.
但斯塔克伍德公司则是二者兼备
But starkwood... they had both.
技术和专长
The technology and the expertise.
那朱玛得给他们提供什么呢
And what did juma have to offer starkwood?
研发武器的安全场所
A safe haven to develop the weapon
和取之不尽的实验品
And an endless supply of victims to test it on.
即使这些都是真的
Even if all this was true,why in the world
那斯塔克伍德公司要生化武器干嘛
Would starkwood want a bioweapon?
参议员  过去的6个月
Senator,you've been trying to dismantle starkwood
你都在努力关闭斯塔克伍德公司
For the last six months.
这可能就是他们所策划的反击
Maybe they planned on fighting back.
但不管怎样  如果他们拥有这样的武器
But regardless,if they have a weapon like this,
你最好做好他们可能使用它的思想准备
You better believe they intend to use it.
迈尔参议员
Senator mayer!
我是首府警察
This is metro pd!
别动
Don't you move.
等等  等等
Hold on. hold on!
很明显  你发现了些线索
You're obviously on to something.
他们能帮你找到证明你清白的证据
They can help you find the evidence you need to prove your case.
现在他们都以为是我杀了伯内特
Right now everyone thinks i killed ryan burnett.
-没人会听我的  -我能保护你
- No one's gonna listen to me. - i can protect you.
我可以命令他们来帮助我们
I can order them to help us.
斯塔克伍德已经渗透到白宫了
Starkwood infiltrated the white house.
一旦他们发现你在追查他们研发
As soon as they find out you're going after them
生化武器一事  就会马上销毁证据的
For a bioweapon,they'll bury the evidence.
那么我们就让知道的人越少越好
Then we'll keep the circle small.
我可以做到的
I can make this happen.
你牺牲了这么多来保护政府
It's time for you to start trusting the institutions
该是你相信它一回的时候了
That you've sacrificed so much to protect.
信任可不是我最大的优点
Trust isn't my greatest asset.
孩子  你总要有所转变
Son,you have to start somewhere.
参议员
Senator!
我是首府警察
This is metro pd!
你真的认为你能做到吗
You really think you can do this?
我对自己有信心
I know i can.
让他们进来吧
Let 'em in.
不
No!
你要见我
You wanted to see me?
是的  利维
Yes,livy.
伊桑刚报告给我一件很恼人的事情
Ethan just come to me with something very disturbing.
我想是有关向媒体透露杰克消息的事吧
I assume it's about the press leak regarding jack bauer.
伊桑觉得你跟这事有关
Ethan seems to think you had something to do with it.
不是我干的
I didn't.
我已经告诉过他了
I already told him that.
鉴于你俩之前的过节  他不相信你
Well,given the past experience between the two of you,he's not convinced.
你怎么认为呢
And what do you think?
我想听听你怎么说
I think i need to hear what you have to say.
她没什么好辩解的  总统阁下
There's nothing she can say,madam president.
只有几个人知道详情
She was one of the few people
她是其中之一
Who knew all the details.
知道的人  比你想象得要多
More people knew than you think.
我刚和CNB电视台的
I just got off the phone
白宫栏目制片人通过电话
with the white house segment producer at CNB.
他不愿透露线人的名字
He won't give me the source's name,
但是他愿意证明
But he's willing to confirm
是联邦执法办里的人走漏了消息
That the leak came from someone inside the Federal Marshal's office.
他担保消息既不是从白宫散布出去的
He'll guarantee it didn't come from the white house,
也不是从我这泄露出去的
Or from me.
可以证明给我看吗
This is verifiable?
制片人的名字叫查理·艾萨克森
Producer's name is charlie isakson.
这是他的电话
Here's his number.
不信的话  你可以亲自打给他
You can call him yourself if you'd like.
我给了艾萨克森一个提议
I offered isakson some
如果他不报道此事  就可以做你的专访
Exclusive time with you if he killed the story,
他同意了
And he agreed.
只要我们拘押鲍尔
So as long as we get bauer in custody,
消息就不会走漏出去了
We should be able to keep the fallout contained.
伊桑  在这种情况下
Ethan,under the circumstances,
我想很明显  是你搞错了
I think it seems clear that you were mistaken.
我对此很满意
I'm satisfied.
你呢
Are you?
我也是  总统阁下
Yes,madam president.
奥利维亚  如果是我错判了当前形势
I'm sorry,olivia, if i misjudged
并错怪了你  我向你道歉
The situation... And you.
我想知道调查局
I want to know
在搜捕鲍尔这事上有什么进展
If the fbi's any closer to finding bauer.
好的  阁下
Yes,ma'am.
就这样吧
That's all.
对不起
I'm sorry
-让你身处如此境地  -我能理解的
- I put you on the spot like that. - i understand.
伊桑让你别无选择
Ethan didn't give you much of a choice.
我只希望
I just hope
他们能在情况变糟之前  找到鲍尔
They find bauer before this gets any worse.
你快不行了
You're dying.
告诉我  武器要运到哪
Just tell me where the weapons are coming in.
什么时间运到
When are they getting here?
已经运到这了
They're already here.
[亚历山大港  C2230区]
Port of Alexandria. Yard C. 2230.
詹尼斯  我是拉里
Janis,it's larry.
我们来晚了一步
We got here too late.
鲍尔杀害了迈尔参议员
Bauer murdered senator mayer.
把搜捕范围扩大到整个地区
Escalate the search for him to region-wide.
通知方圆50英里内所有分部调派增援
I want reinforcements from every branch Within 50 miles brought into this.
收到
Copy that.
鉴于目前形势
At this point...
我授权你们一见嫌犯  格杀勿论
Orders are to shoot on sight.
喂
Yeah.
托尼  我是杰克
Tony,it's jack.
杰克  我一直监视着调查局的线路
Jack,i've been monitoring the fbi bandwidth.
到底发生什么了
What the hell's going on?
兄弟  我需要你的帮助  你在哪
Listen,man,i need your help. where are you?
第三大街和B大街交汇口
3rd street and b.
好  听我说  我们在亚历山大港见面
Okay,listen to me,i need you to meet me at the port of alexandria.
带上武器  还有侦测设备
I need you to bring a weapons and a surveillance package.
-尽快赶到那里  -杰克  等等
- Get there as soon as possible. - jack,wait.
来不及了  路上我再打给你
I can't. i'll get back to you as soon as i'm en route.